The legend ends.
The Dark Knight Rises is a action, crime, drama
film directed by Christopher Nolan.
Following the death of District Attorney Harvey Dent, Batman assumes responsibility for Dent's crimes to protect
the late attorney's reputation and is subsequently hunted by the Gotham City Police Department.
Eight years later, Batman encounters the mysterious Selina Kyle and the
villainous Bane, a new terrorist leader who overwhelms Gotham's finest.
The Dark Knight resurfaces to protect a city that has branded him an enemy.
Bruce Wayne, played by Christian Bale.
Commissioner Gordon, played by Gary Oldman.
Bane, played by Tom Hardy.
Blake, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
Selina, played by Anne Hathaway.
Miranda, played by Marion Cotillard.
The Dark Knight Rises is a 2012 superhero film based
on the DC Comics character Batman.
Directed by Christopher Nolan, who co-wrote the screenplay with his
brother Jonathan Nolan, and the story with David S.
Goyer, it is the final installment in Nolan's The Dark Knight
trilogy, and the sequel to The Dark Knight (2008).
The film stars Christian Bale as Bruce Wayne / Batman, alongside Anne Hathaway, Gary Oldman, Tom
Hardy, Morgan Freeman, Marion Cotillard, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, and Michael Caine.
Set eight years after the events of The Dark Knight, it follows a retired Wayne being forced to resume his role as
Batman to save Gotham City from nuclear destruction at the hands of the terrorist Bane (Hardy).
Christopher Nolan was hesitant about returning to the series for a third film, but agreed after developing a
story with his brother and Goyer that he felt would conclude the series on a satisfactory note.
Nolan drew inspiration from Bane's comic book debut in the 1993 "Knightfall" storyline, the
1986 series The Dark Knight Returns, and the 1999 storyline "No Man's Land".
Filming took place from May to November 2011 in locations including Jodhpur, London,
Nottingham, Glasgow, Los Angeles, New York City, Newark, and Pittsburgh.
Nolan used IMAX 70 mm film cameras for much of the filming, including the first
six minutes of the film, to optimize the quality of the picture.
A vehicle variation of the Batplane and Batcopter termed the "Bat", an underground
prison set, and a new Batcave set were created specially for the film.
As with The Dark Knight, viral marketing
campaigns began early during production.
When filming concluded, Warner Bros.
refocused its campaign, developing promotional websites, releasing the first six minutes of the film,
screening theatrical trailers, and sending out information regarding the film's plot.
The Dark Knight Rises premiered in New York City on July 16, 2012, and was
released in the United States and the United Kingdom on July 20.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who deemed
it a satisfying conclusion to the trilogy.
It received a nomination for Special Visual Effects at the 66th British Academy Film Awards, and numerous other
accolades, in addition to being named one of the top-ten films of 2012 by the American Film Institute.
It also grossed $1.115 billion worldwide, making it the second film in the Batman film
series to earn $1 billion, and the highest-grossing Batman film to date.
In addition to being Nolan's highest-grossing film, it became the seventh-highest-grossing film of all
time at the time of its release, as well as the third-highest-grossing film of 2012.
The film explores themes of airplane, fight, burglar, hostage, secret identity.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.